Arna Bontemps Papers
Arna Bontemps Papers
- Correspondence-Subject Files
  - Harcourt, Brace and Company, Inc. (Box 11)
  - Harcourt, Brace & World, Inc. (Box 11)
  - Harlem Cultural Council, 1966; exhibition catalog (Box 11)
  - "Harlem U.S.A." (WMCA radio program) (Box 11)
  - Harmon Foundation (Box 11)
  - Harper & Brothers (Box 11)
  - Harper & Row (Box 11)
  - Harper's Magazine (Box 11)
  - Harrison, William (Box 11)
  - Hartog, Jan de, See De Hartog, Jan.
  - Hayden, Robert Earl (Box 11)
  - Hayes, Donald J. (Box 11)
  - Haygood, William C. (Box 11)
  - Hazel, Robert (Box 11)
  - Head School (Nashville, Tenn.) (Box 11)
  - Hemenway, Robert (Box 11)
  - Henry, Myrtle Catherine (Box 11)
  - Hesse, Eva (Box 11)
  - Hicklin, Fannie Ella Frazier (Box 11)
  - Highroad (Box 11)
  - Hill, Herbert (Box 11)
  - Hill, Roy L. (Box 11)
  - Hill and Wang, Inc., 1961-1967; 4 folders (Box 11, 12)
  - Hines, Carl Wendell (Box 12)
  - Hines, Ida E. ("Aunt Idoo") (Box 12)
  - Hogins, James Burl (Box 12)
  - Hohmann, Walter H. (Box 12)
  - Holman, M. Carl (Box 12)
  - Holt, Nora Douglas (Box 12)
  - Holt, Rackham (Box 12)
  - [Henry] Holt and Company, Inc. see, See Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc..
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc. (Box 12)
  - Hopper, Franklin Ferguson (Box 12)
  - Horn Book, Inc. (Box 12)
  - Horne, Frank S. (Box 12)
  - Hotel Theresa (New York, N.Y.) (Box 12)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1937-1968; undated; 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Howard University (Box 12)
  - Howland, Frances (Box 12)
  - Huber, Miriam Blanton (Box 12)
  - Hudlin, Warrington (Box 12)
  - Hudson, David (Box 12)
  - Huff, William Henry (Box 12)
  - Huggins, Kathryn Laverne (Box 12)
  - Hughes, Langston
    - Correspondence relating to expanded The Poetry of the Negro, 1939-1967; undated; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Anthology manuscripts
      - "Cats, Crickets, and Stars" (Box 13)
      - "Poems That Just Grew" (Box 13)
      - "Spread My Wings and Fly" (Box 13)
      - "That's a Moon" (Box 13)
    - Essay manuscripts
      - "My Early Days in Harlem" (Box 13)
    - Playscripts
      - "Don't You Want to Be Free?" (Centennial version: 1963) (Box 13)
      - "Emperor of Haiti", 2 copies; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - "Esther" (Box 13)
      - "The Gospel Glory", 2 copies; 2 folders (Box 14)
      - "The Gospel Glow", "revised rehearsal script" (Box 14)
      - "Jerico-Jim-Crow", "final revised acting script" (Box 14)
      - "Just Around the Corner" (Box 14)
      - "Little Ham" (Box 14)
      - "Mulatto" (Box 14)
      - "Mule Bone" - "Spring, 1930" (Box 14)
      - "Mule Bone" - "Jeliffe-[Karamu] House" (Box 14)
      - "The Prodigal Son" (Box 14)
      - "Simple Takes a Wife" (Box 14)
      - "Simply Heaven" (Box 14)
      - "Soul Gone Home" (Box 14)
      - "The Sun Do Move", 2 copies; 2 folders (Box 14)
      - "Tambourines to Glory" (Box 15)
  - Hunt, Evelyn Tooley (Box 15)
  - Hunter, Alberta (Box 15)
  - Huntley, Leston (Box 15)
    See also Writings: Miscellaneous: "The Sunny Side of the Street".
  - Hylton, Richard (Box 15)
  - Hyman, Stanley Edgar (Box 15)
  - I (Box 15)
  - Illinois State University (Normal) (Box 15)
  - Illinois Teachers College (Box 15)
  - Indiana University Press (Box 15)
  - Ingram, Rex (Box 15)
  - International Institute of Arts and Letters (Box 15)
  - International Press Agency Ltd. (Box 15)
  - International Publishers (Box 15)
  - Italiaander, R. B. M. (Box 15)
  - J (Box 15)
  - Jack and Jill (Box 15)
  - Jackman, Harold (Box 15)
  - Jackson, Blyden (Box 15)
  - Jackson, Booker T. (Box 15)
  - Jackson, Mahalia (Box 15)
  - Jacobsen, Josephine (Box 15)
  - Jelliffe, Rowena Woodham (Box 15)
  - Jenkins, Welborn Victor (Box 15)
  - Joans, Ted (Box 15)
  - John Street Baptist Church (Worcester, Mass.) (Box 15)
  - Johnson, Benjamin Tanner (Box 15)
  - Johnson, Charles Spurgeon, printed material by and about Johnson, Opportunity submissions, manuscript writings, notes, miscellany; 11 folders (Box 15, 16)
    See also Fisk University.
  - Johnson, Dorothy (Box 17)
  - Johnson, Ethel A. (Box 17)
  - Johnson, Georgia Douglas Camp (Box 17)
  - Johnson, Helene (Box 17)
  - Johnson Publishing Company, Inc. (Box 17)
  - Jones, Eldred D. (Box 17)
  - Jones, Laurence C. (Box 17)
  - Jones, LeRoi, See also Baraka, Imamu Amiri.
  - Jones, Savannah (Box 17)
  - Jordan, Joe (Box 17)
  - Jordan, Norman (Box 17)
  - K, 1 folder (Box 17)
  - Kanin, Garson (Box 17)
  - Karamu House (Cleveland, Ohio), See Jelliffe, Rowena Woodham.
  - Kariara, Jonathan - "The Green Bean Patch", script (Box 17)
  - Kay, Ulysses (Box 17)
  - Kennedy, Raymond (Box 17)
  - Kent, George E. (Box 17)
  - Kentucky State College (Box 17)
  - Killens, John Oliver (Box 17)
  - Kinnamon, Keneth (Box 17)
  - Knollenberg, Bernhard (Box 17)
  - [Alfred A.] Knopf, Inc., 1941-1970; undated; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Knoxville College (Box 17)
  - Kornweibel, Theodore (Box 17)
  - Koshland, Miriam G. (Box 17)
  - L (Box 17)
  - LaMarre, Hazel (Box 17)
  - Lane, Wilson H. (Box 17)
  - Langston University (Box 17)
  - Larimer, Mary Ogden (Box 17)
  - Larrick, Nancy (Box 17)
  - Larsen, Carl (Box 17)
  - Lawrence, Jacob (Box 17)
  - Lawson, Edward (Box 17)
  - Lazar, Irving Paul (Box 17)
  - League of Allied Arts (Los Angeles, Calif.) (Box 17)
  - Lee, George Washington (Box 17)
  - Lee, Lloyd L. (Box 17)
  - Lee, Mollie Huston (Box 17)
  - LeMoyne College (Memphis, Tenn.) (Box 17)
  - Lennon, Florence Becker (Box 17)
  - Leonardi, Leon (Box 17)
  - Lesser, Sol (Box 17)
  - Lester, Julius (Box 17)
  - Lherisson, Camille (Box 17)
  - Liberty Book Club, Inc. (Box 17)
  - Library Journal (Box 17)
  - Lieber, Maxim, 1940-1963; 8 folders (Box 17, 18)
  - Lieber, Minna Edith, See Maxim, Lieber.
  - Lincoln, Charles Eric (Box 18)
  - Lincoln Institute of Kentucky (Box 18)
  - Lincoln University (Jefferson City, Mo.) (Box 18)
  - Linden, Margaret (Box 18)
  - Link, Carolyn (Box 18)
  - Link, Gordden (Box 18)
  - Lipton, Lawrence (Box 18)
  - Litten, Frederic Nelson (Box 18)
  - Little, Brown & Company (Box 18)
  - Liveright Publishing Corporation (Box 18)
  - Livsey, Rosemary E. (Box 18)
  - Llorens, Lucille (Box 18)
  - Lochard, Metz, See The Chicago Defender.
  - Locke, Alain LeRoy (Box 18)
  - Long, Herman Hodge (Box 18)
  - Lorde, Audre (Box 18)
  - Los Angeles Public Library (Box 18)
  - Louisiana Education Association (Box 18)
  - Love, Rose Leary (Box 18)
  - Lowenfels, Walter (Box 18)
  - Lucas, Robert "A Dramatization of Black Thunder", script (Box 18)
  - Luce, Clare Boothe (Box 18)
  - Luckhardt, Mildred Madeleine Corell (Box 18)
  - LuValle, James E. (Box 18)
  - M, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - MacDowell Colony (Box 19)
  - McGinnis, Frederick A. (Box 19)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company (Box 19)
  - McKay, Claude (Box 19)
  - McLaren, Ken (Box 19)
  - Macleod, Norman (Box 19)
  - Macmillan Company (Box 19)
  - Mahadevan, T. K. (Box 19)
  - Major, Clarence (Box 19)
  - Makerere College (Kampala, Uganda) (Box 19)
  - Maltz, Albert (Box 19)
  - Mamoulian, Rouben (Box 19)
  - Mardus, Elaine (Box 19)
  - Margolies, Edward (Box 19)
  - Marinoff, Fania (Box 19)
  - Market Place Gallery (New York, N.Y.) (Box 19)
  - Marks, Jeannette Augustus (Box 19)
  - Marshall, Thurgood (Box 19)
  - Martinez, Maurice (Box 19)
  - Maxon, Constance M. (Box 19)
  - Meadowcroft, Enid La Monte, See Grosset & Dunlap, Inc..
  - Means, Carl (Box 19)
  - Means, Florence Crannell (Box 19)
  - Meier, August (Box 19)
  - Meltzer, Milton, 1953-1967; 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Memphis (Tenn.) city schools (Box 20)
  - Menarini, Gianni (Box 20)
  - The Message Magazine (Box 20)
  - [Julian] Messner, Inc. (Box 20)
  - The Methodist Church (Box 20)
  - Meyer, Annie Nathan (Box 20)
  - Michel, Lois A. (Box 20)
  - Micheline, Jack (Box 20)
  - Michigan Library Association (Box 20)
  - Midwestern Writers' Conference (Box 20)
  - Millender, Dharathula H. (Box 20)
  - Millet, Garland see Oakwood College
  - Milwaukee Public Library (Box 20)
  - Minneapolis Teachers League (Box 20)
  - Mitchell, Loften (Box 20)
  - Mkapa, Benjamin W. (Box 20)
  - Mobile Teachers' Association (Box 20)
  - Modisane, Bloke, "The Situation" manuscript (Box 20)
  - Moon, Bucklin (Box 20)
    See also Doubleday & Company, Inc..
  - Moore, George Curtis (Box 20)
  - Moore, Gerald (Box 20)
  - Moore, William L. (Box 20)
  - Mopper, Irving (Box 20)
  - Morgan State College (Baltimore, Maryland) (Box 20)
  - [William] Morrow & Company, Inc. (Box 20)
  - Moss, Carlton (Box 20)
  - Most, Marty (Box 20)
  - Moten, Etta (Box 20)
  - Motley, Willard (Box 20)
  - Mottram, Eric (Box 20)
  - Mouzon, Brunetta, "Popo and Fifina" script (Box 20)
  - Mumford, Lewis (Box 20)
  - Munger, Edwin S. (Box 20)
  - Munson, Gorham (Box 20)
  - Murphy, Beatrice M. (Box 20)
  - Murphy, Carl, See Afro-American Newspapers.
  - Murray, Pauli (Box 20)
  - Murray State College (Ky.) (Box 20)
  - N (Box 20)
  - Nashville, Tennessee (Box 20)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) (Box 21)
  - National Council of Negro Women, Inc. (Box 21)
  - National Council of Teachers of English (Box 21)
  - National Negro Congress (Chicago) (Box 21)
  - National Tuberculosis Association (Box 21)
  - National Urban League (Box 21)
  - Negro American Literature Forum, See Bayliss, John F..
  - Negro Book Society (Box 21)
  - Negro Digest (Box 21)
    See also Fuller, Hoyt W..
  - Negro Radio Workshop, See Lawson, Edward.
  - Neider, Charles (Box 21)
  - New School for Social Research (Box 21)
  - New York Herald Tribune (Box 21)
  - New York Public Library (Box 21)
  - The New York Times (Box 21)
  - Newman, Isidora (Box 21)
  - Newsome, Effie Lee (Box 21)
  - Nichol, Francis David (Box 21)
  - Nineteenth Century Women's Club (Oak Park, Ill.) (Box 21)
  - Njau, Rebeka, "The Scar" script (Box 21)
  - Norfolk (Va.) school libraries (Box 21)
  - Norford, George (Box 21)
  - Norlev, Erling (Box 21)
  - North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company (Box 21)
  - North Carolina Negro Library Association, See Bennett College.
  - Norway, Nevil Shute, See Shute, Nevil.
  - O (Box 21)
  - Oak Park (Mich.) Public Library (Box 21)
  - Oakwood College (Huntsville, Ala.) (Box 21)
  - Oden, Gloria (Box 21)
  - Odunewu, Alade (Box 21)
  - O'Hara, Frank Hurburt (Box 22)
  - O'Higgins, Myron (Box 22)
  - Ohl, John F. (Box 22)
  - Oklahoma State University (Box 22)
  - Oliver, Diane A. (Box 22)
  - Omega Psi Phi Fraternity, Inc. (Box 22)
  - O'Neal, Frederick (Box 22)
  - O'Neal, Regina S. (Box 22)
  - Ortiz Oderigo, Nestor R. (Box 22)
  - Osborne, Juanita Tyree (Box 22)
  - Ottley, Roi (Box 22)
  - Ovington, Mary White (Box 22)
  - Oxford University Press (Box 22)
  - P (Box 22)
  - Pacific Union College (Box 22)
  - Packwood, Cyril Outerbridge (Box 22)
  - Palfi, Marion (Box 22)
  - Pankey, Aubrey and Kay, See Seven Seas Publishers.
  - Parkway Community House (Chicago) (Box 22)
  - Pasadena Inter-Racial Women's Club (Box 22)
  - Patchen, Kenneth (Box 22)
  - Patterson, Frederick Douglass, See Tuskegee Institute
  - Patterson, Ray (Box 22)
  - P.E.N.
    - Letters (Box 22)
    - Postcards (Box 22)
    - Printed material, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Peare, Catherine Owens (Box 22)
  - Pearl High School (Nashville, Tenn.) (Box 22)
  - Pegler, Westbrook (Box 22)
  - Pennsylvania Library Association (Box 22)
  - Petersen, Sydney Vernon (Box 22)
  - Peterson, Dorothy (Box 22)
  - Phelps-Stokes Fund (Box 23)
  - Phi Delta Kappa (Box 23)
  - Phi Mu Alpha Sinfonia Fraternity of America (Box 23)
  - Phylon (Box 23)
  - Picott, Rupert (Box 23)
  - Piquion, Rene (Box 23)
  - Pitcher, Oliver (Box 23)
  - The Pittsburgh Courier (Box 23)
  - Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc. (Box 23)
  - Plymouth Congregational Church (Detroit, Mich.) (Box 23)
  - Poag, Thomas E. (Box 23)
  - Pool, Rosey E. (Box 23)
  - Porter, Dorothy Burnett, See Howard University.
  - Porter, Kenneth Wiggins (Box 23)
  - Poston, Ted (Box 23)
  - Powers, James Farl (Box 23)
  - Preece, Harold (Box 23)
  - Preminger, Alex (Box 23)
  - Prentice-Hall International, Inc. (Box 23)
  - Presence Africaine (Box 23)
  - Primeau, Ronald (Box 23)
  - Public Library of Winston-Salem and Forsyth County (N.C.) (Box 23)
  - [G. P.] Putnam's Sons (Box 23)
  - Q (Box 23)
  - Quint, Catherine (Box 23)
  - R (Box 23)
  - Ralston, Richard (Box 23)
  - Randall, Dudley (Box 23)
  - Ransom, John Crowe (Box 23)
  - Raymond, Margaret T. (Box 23)
  - Redd, George N., See Fisk University.
  - Reddick, Lawrence Dunbar (Box 23)
    See also New York Public Library.
  - Redding, Jay Saunders (Box 23)
  - Reed, Ishmael (Box 23)
  - Reid, Ira DeAugustine (Box 23)
    See also Du Bois, William Edward Burghardt.
  - Reines, Bernard Jacob (Box 23)
  - Reynolds, Louis Bernard (Box 23)
  - Richardson, Joe Martin (Box 23)
  - Rider, Ione Morrison (Box 23)
  - Rinehart & Company, Inc., See Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc..
  - Rive, Richard (Box 23)
  - Rivers, Conrad Kent (Box 23)
  - Robbins, Richard (Box 23)
  - Roberson, Ed (Box 23)
  - Robeson, Paul (Box 23)
  - Robinson, Armstead Louis (Box 23)
  - Rollins, Charlemae Hill (Box 23)
  - Ronald, Rolanda (Box 23)
  - Rosenberg, Dorothy (Box 23)
  - Rosenwald, Lessing Julius (Box 23)
  - [Julius] Rosenwald Fund, 1938-1949; undated; 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Row, Peterson & Company (Box 24)
  - Rowan, Carl Thomas (Box 24)
  - Roy, Savannah, See Jones, Savannah.
  - Rubin, Louis Decimus (Box 24)
  - Rutland, Eva (Box 24)
  - S, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Saher, Lilla van (Box 24)
  - St. James Literary Forum (Cleveland, Ohio) (Box 24)
  - Salisbury, Leah (Box 24)
  - Salk, Erwin A. (Box 24)
  - San Francisco Negro Historical and Cultural Society (Box 24)
  - Sanford, Isabel (Box 24)
  - The Saturday Evening Post (Box 24)
  - The Saturday Review of Literature (Box 24)
  - Savannah State College (Box 24)
  - Savoy, Willard W. (Box 24)
  - Saxon, Dan (Box 24)
  - Scheer, George F., See World Publishing Company.
  - Scholastic Magazines, Inc. (Box 24)
  - Schuyler, George Samuel and Josephine (Box 24)
  - Scott, Emmett J. (Box 24)
  - Scott, Hazel (Box 24)
  - Scott, Foresman and Company (Box 24)
  - Seuell, Malchus M. (Box 24)
  - Seven Seas Publishers (Box 24)
  - Seventh-day Adventists (Box 24)
  - Shank, Mary (Box 25)
  - Sharon, Henrietta Bruce (Box 25)
  - Shedd, Margaret Cochran (Box 25)
  - Sheldon, William D. (Box 25)
  - Shute, Nevil (Box 25)
  - Sigma Pi Phi, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Silver, Reuben (Box 25)
  - Simon, Adelaide (Box 25)
  - Simon and Schuster, Inc. (Box 25)
  - [L. W.] Singer Company (Box 25)
  - Smallwood, Bill (Box 25)
  - Smith, Arthur Lee (Box 25)
  - Smith, Earle C. (Box 25)
  - Smith, Jeffrey H. (Box 25)
  - Smith, Mary Carter (Box 25)
  - Smythe, Hugh and Mabel (Box 25)
  - Snellings, Rolland (Box 25)
  - Society of Midland Authors (Box 25)
  - Soper, Francis A. (Box 25)
  - Southern University (Baton Rouge, La.) (Box 25)
  - Spellman, A. B. (Box 25)
  - Spencer, Anne (Box 25)
  - Spingarn, Amy (Box 25)
  - Spingarn, Arthur B. (Box 25)
  - Spivack, Bernard (Box 25)
  - Spivey, Lenore W. (Box 25)
  - State Agricultural and Mechanical College, Orangeburg, South Carolina (Box 25)
  - State Teachers College (Montgomery, Ala.), See Alabama State College.
  - Sterling, Dorothy (Box 25)
  - Stewart, Donald Ogden and Ella Winter (Box 25)
  - Still, Verna Arvey, See Arvey, Verna.
  - Still, William Grant (Box 25)
  - Stock, Mildred (Box 25)
  - Stoff, Michael B. (Box 25)
  - Stokes, Anna J., "The Autobiography of Anna J. Stokes" manuscript (Box 25)
  - Stokes, Olivia Egleston Phelps (Box 25)
  - Sutton, William Alfred (Box 25)
  - Swank, Raynard Coe (Box 25)
  - T (Box 25)
  - Talladega College (Box 25)
  - Tarn, Nathaniel (Box 25)
  - Tarry, Ellen (Box 25)
  - Taylor, Margaret, See Burroughs, Margaret Taylor.
  - Taylor, Patricia E. (Box 25)
  - Teachers Union of the City of New York (Box 26)
  - Telluride Association (Box 26)
  - Temple, Ruth Janetta (Box 26)
  - Tennessee Agricultural and Industrial State College (Box 26)
  - Tennessee Agricultural and Industrial State University (Box 26)
  - Tennessee Education Congress (Box 26)
  - Tennessee Library Association (Box 26)
  - Terrell, Mary Church (Box 26)
  - Texas Southern University (Box 26)
  - Texas State University for Negroes (Box 26)
  - Thomas, Richard W. (Box 26)
  - Thompson, Charles Hubbard (Box 26)
  - Thompson, Era Bell (Box 26)
  - Thomson, Virgil (Box 26)
  - Time (Box 26)
  - Tinker, Edward Laroque (Box 26)
  - Tolson, Melvin Beaunorus (Box 26)
  - Tomorrow (Box 26)
  - Toomer, Jean
    - Manuscripts
      - "Meridian Hill", holograph manuscript (Box 26)
      - "The Wayward and the Seeking", typescript manuscript (Box 26)
      - "Winter Road", typescript manuscript (Box 26)
    - Material related to the Jean Toomer Papers at Fisk University (Box 26)
  - Toomer, Marjorie Content (Box 26)
  - Torrence, Ridgely (Box 26)
  - Torres, John (Box 26)
  - Tottress, Richard E. (Box 26)
  - Trounstine, John J., See Turner, John B..
  - Troy, Owen and Ruby (Box 26)
  - Tunis, John Roberts (Box 26)
  - Turner, Darwin T. (Box 26)
  - Turner, John B., 1937-1950; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Turner, Lorenzo Dow (Box 26)
  - Tuskegee Institute, 2 folders (Box 27)
  - [Charles E.] Tuttle Company (Box 27)
  - U, 1 folder (Box 27)
  - United States. Work Projects Administration (Box 27)
  - University of California, 1963-1966; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - University of Chicago (Box 27)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle, 1966-1968; undated; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - University of Minnesota (Box 27)
  - University of Wisconsin (Box 27)
  - Unterecker, John (Box 27)
  - V, 1 folder (Box 27)
  - Van Vechten, Carl, 1939-1943; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Van Vechten, Carl, 1944-1954; undated; 6 folders (Box 28)
  - Viking Press, Inc. (Box 28)
  - Virginia Teachers Association (Box 28)
  - Voorhees, Lillian Welch (Box 28)
  - W, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - WCFL (Chicago) (Box 28)
  - WTTW (Chicago) (Box 28)
  - Wagner, Jean (Box 28)
  - Walcutt, Charles Child (Box 28)
  - Walden, Daniel (Box 28)
  - Walker, Alice (Box 28)
  - Walker, Margaret (Box 28)
  - Warfel, Harry Redcay (Box 28)
  - Warren County (N.C.) Supervisors Office (Box 28)
  - Watkins, Sylvestre C. (Box 28)
  - Watts, Schuyler (Box 28)
  - Waxman, Julia, See [Julius] Rosenwald Fund.
  - Webster, Harvey Curtis (Box 28)
  - Weiss, Alexander (Box 28)
  - Welch, Marie de L. (Box 28)
  - Westerman, George W. (Box 28)
  - Wheeler, Charles Enoch (Box 29)
  - White, Clarence Cameron (Box 29)
  - White, Nathaniel B. (Box 29)
  - White, Walter Francis (Box 29)
  - [John Hay] Whitney Foundation (Box 29)
  - Wideman, John Edgar (Box 29)
  - Wiley College (Marshall, Texas) (Box 29)
  - Wilkins, Roy (Box 29)
  - Williams, Clarence (Box 29)
  - Williams, Eugene (Box 29)
  - Williams, Fred Hart (Box 29)
  - Williams, John (Box 29)
  - Williams, Wilson A. (Box 29)
  - Wills, Frances (Box 29)
  - Wilson, Ernest J. (Box 29)
  - [John C.] Winston Company, 1947-1957; 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Winter, Ella, See Stewart, Donald Ogden and Ella Winter.
  - Wofford, Azile (Box 29)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (Box 29)
  - Wood, Milton (Box 29)
  - Woods, Porter (Box 29)
  - Work, John Wesley (Box 29)
  - World Publishing Company (Box 29)
  - Worthy, Ruth (Box 29)
  - Wright, Bruce McMarion (Box 29)
  - Wright, Charles (Box 29)
  - Wright, Jay (Box 29)
  - Wright, Richard (Box 29)
  - Writers' Conference (Evanston, Ill.), See Midwestern Writers' Conference.
  - Y (Box 29)
  - Yaddo (Box 29)
  - Yale University Library (Box 29)
  - Yates, Elizabeth (Box 29)
  - Young Women's Christian Association (Box 29)
  - Z (Box 29)
  - Zangrando, Robert L. (Box 29)
  - Fan mail, 1938-1955 (Box 29)
  - Fan mail, 1956-1970; undated; 4 folders (Box 30)
  - Unidentified (Box 30)
- Writings
  - Articles and essays
    - "The Administration of Fisk University", notes, typescript manuscript (Box 31)
    - "American Missionary Association Archives in Fisk University Library", typescript carbon; brochure (Nashville, 1947) (Box 31)
    - "American Negro Poetry", typescript manuscripts, including a French translation "La Poesie Noire Americaine" (Box 31)
    - "An American Original," Tomorrow, June 1945 (Box 31)
    - "The Awakening: a Memoir", typescript manuscript
    - "Banneker's Strange 'Disturbance," The Message Magazine, Sept. 1950 (Box 31)
    - "Black & Bubbling," The Saturday Review, Apr. 5, 1952 (Box 31)
    - "Blues", typescript manuscript (Box 31)
    - "The Boy Who Wasn't Sure," Classmate, Mar. 1945 (Box 31)
    - "Buried Treasures of Negro Art," Negro Digest, Dec. 1950; typescript manuscripts (Box 31)
    - "Chestnutt Papers Go to Fisk" - Library Journal, Aug. 1952; typescript carbon (offprint) (Box 31)
    - "Children's Books and American Unity," Northwestern University On the Air, Nov. 18, 1942; transcript of radio conversation (Box 31)
    - "Countee Cullen," Film News, Jan. 1946 (Box 31)
    - "Countee Cullen: American Poet" - The People's Voice, Jan. 26, 1946; dust jacket copy: Hold Fast to Dreams "7-8-68" manuscript (Box 31)
    - "Even Money on John Chavis," Common Ground; "Even Money Bet on John Chavis," Negro Digest, Autumn 1949; Feb. 1950; typescript (Box 31)
    - "The Exodus Train" (excerpt from They Seek a City), Common Ground, Spring 1945 (Box 31)
    - "Facing a Dilemma," The Saturday Review, Feb. 16, 1952 (Box 31)
    - "Famous WPA Authors," Negro Digest, June 1950; typescript manuscripts; carbon typescript title "Famous Authors of WPA" (Box 31)
    - "Fiddler's Progress," Young People (American Baptist Publication Society), Apr. 1, 1945 (Box 31)
    - "Fisk University Library" - Fisk News, Feb. 1956; typescript manuscripts (Box 31)
    - "Foreword: Selected Items from the George Gershwin Memorial Collection of Music and Musical Literature", undated; typescript manuscripts; brochure (Nashville: Fisk University Library) (Box 31)
    - Grolier Encyclopedia biographies (Box 31)
    - "Half a Life," The Message Magazine, Vol. XII, no. 10 (Box 32)
    - "Harlem in the Twenties," The Crisis, Oct. 1966 (Box 32)
    - "The Harlem Renaissance," The Saturday Review, Mar. 22, 1947 (Box 32)
    - "Harlem: the 'Beautiful' Years," Negro Digest, Jan. 1965 (Box 32)
    - "He Got Fired!" Classmate, Jan. 1945 (Box 32)
    - "He Was Fired," Pilgrim Neighborhood, Feb. 1947 (Box 32)
    - "How I Told My Child About Race," Negro Digest, May 1951; typescript manuscript (Box 32)
    - "How 'St. Louis Woman' Was Born", typescript manuscript (Box 32)
    - "How You Get T.B.," The Message Magazine, June 1947; typescript manuscript (Box 32)
    - "Hughes, (James Mercer) Langston" from Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1969 (Box 32)
    - "I Press On!" Classmate, Apr. 1945 (Box 32)
    - "I Remember," Topic no. 5, typescript manuscripts (Box 32)
    - "In Choosing a College", typescript manuscripts; brochure (Nashville: Fisk University, 1953?) (Box 32)
    - Introductions
      - The Autobiography of an Ex-Colored Man / by James Weldon Johnson, typescript manuscripts (Box 32)
      - Biographical notes for Folkways Records recording (FP90) of readings by Sterling Brown and Langston Hughes, typescript manuscripts; printed material (artwork by Jacob Lawrence) (Box 32)
      - Un Chant Nouveau / by Langston Hughes (Port-au-Prince, Haiti: Imprimerie de l'Etat), undated; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
      - Black Thunder / by Arna Bontemps, typescript manuscript; photocopy from Boston: Beacon Press, 1968 edition (Box 32)
      - Cane / by Jean Toomer, research notes; typescript manuscript; photocopy from New York: Harper & Row, c1969 edition (Box 32)
      - Christmas Gif' / by Charlemae Rollins, typescript manuscripts (Box 32)
      - Don't You Turn Back / poems by Langston Hughes, selected by Lee Bennett Hopkins, typescript manuscript; photocopy from New York: Knopf, c1967, 1969 edition (Box 32)